Zachary Handel

zachary.handelzh@gmail.com 256-947-1235

GitHub: https://github.com/ZacharyHandel

Professional Summary

Experienced Full-Stack Software Developer knowledgeable in creating efficient software solutions for different areas of technology. Combines skills of known programming languages, frameworks, version control tools, issue tracking tools, development lifecycles, and other technical skills to produce and maintain high quality software.

Work Experience

nSide, Inc.

Junior Web Developer Intern

May 2024-Current May 2023-May 2024

- Developed and maintained web applications and API's using ASP.NET, VB.NET, HTML5, CSS, C#, JavaScript, and MySQL while following MVC and MVVM architectures.
- Participated in agile development and software lifecycle standards.
- Utilized Atlassian Jira for issue tracking.
- Participated in functional software testing on landing page, nSide | Plans, nSide | Edge, and nSide | Lockdown.
- Utilized Git and GitHub for version control.
- Provided technical documentation related to software maintenance research and requirements.
- Participated in sprint-planning, status, and stand-up meetings.
- Proposed prototype solutions to the team for given requirements from stakeholders.

DigiSigns

Web Developer

April 2023-May 2023

- Developed and maintained the landing page using Next.js.
- Developed and maintained the sales application's front-end using Next.js.
- Participated in establishing the software lifecycle for startup company.
- Participated in agile development.

Peraton

Intern

May 2022-Aug. 2022

- Helped to keep data accessible and organized with consistent database updates.
- Prepared and maintained records of meetings and documents reviewed in accordance with assigned projects.
- Participated in meetings and conferences as assigned by team leader.
- Tested database and entered equipment inventory data via Microsoft Access

- Consolidated computer hardware for field use
- Executed functional testing on the FlightViz and FlightAnalyst flight training simulation software

Education

University of North Alabama

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Minor: Cyber Security

Florence, AL

May 2024

GPA: 3.45

Skills

- Full-Stack Development
- Agile Development
- JavaScript
- Python
- API Integration
- HTML5
- CSS
- Angular.JS
- Node.js
- Git
- GitHub
- Troubleshooting
- Application debugging

- Interface design
- Software testing
- TypeScript
- jQuery
- Bootstrap
- MySQL
- Next.js
- Atlassian Jira
- C#
- ASP.NET
- C++
- C
- VB.NET
- MySQLite3

Projects

Navigate to the provided <u>GitHub</u> link at the top of the document.

References

Available upon request.